다이간다는 방을 밝게 하고 적당히 떨어져서 봐!
Watch Daigunder in a bright room and keep some distance!
Смотри Дайгандера со включённым светом, сидя подальше от экрана!
다이간다!
Daigunder!
Дайгандер!
다다다다다다다다다!
Dadadada da da da dada
Дададада-да-да-да-дада!
다다다다다다다다다!
Dadadada da da da dada
Дададада-да-да-да-дада!
다이 다이 다이 다이 다이간다
Dai Dai Dai Dai Daigunder
Дай-Дай-Дай-Дай-Дайгандер
불타라 불타올라라
Burn and flare up
Пыл борьбы разожги ты в себе,
마음의 눈을 열어라
Open your eyes of soul
Распахни шире око души
폭투선언 다이간다
Wild Fight Declaration Daigunder!
(Bakutou Sengen Daigunder)
Боевой претендент Дайгандер!
뜨거운 마음을 담아
With all your hot heart
Пусть меня охватит твой жар сердца,
오늘도 기적을 맹새해
I will make a miracle today too
Чтобы сотворить сумел я чудо
드래곤 소드 작렬이야
Dragon Sword bursts
Вспыхнет ярким светом Меч Дракона!
싸워야 할 라이벌은
The rival I have to fight against is
Побороть я должен свой упавший дух,
좌절하려는 내 자신
right here, dispirited myself
что пути к успеху преграждает мне,
어제보다도 진화해서
Evolve even more than yesterday
Вырасти сегодня больше, чем вчера
강해져라!
And become strong!
И сильнее стать!
다다다다 다 다 다 다다
Dadadada da da da dada
Дададада-да-да-да-дада!
드래곤 캐논!
Dragon Cannon!
Пушка Дракона!
다이 다이 다이 다이 다이간다
Dai Dai Dai Dai Daigunder
Дай-Дай-Дай-Дай-Дайгандер
불타라 불타올라라
Burn and flare up
Пыл борьбы разожги ты в себе
에너지 전개로
Open up all your energy and
Дай энергии выход, сказав...
다다다다다다 다
Dadadadadada da
Дададададада-да!!
다이 다이 다이 다이 다이간다
Dai Dai Dai Dai Daigunder
Дай-Дай-Дай-Дай-Дайгандер
쓰러트려라 타도해라
Defeat and knock down
Победи и врагов одолей
빛나는 강철의
Fighter of shining steel
Сталью сверкает тело твоё,
폭투선언 다이간다
Wild Fight Declaration Daigunder
Боевой претендент Дайгандер
제 23 화
The 23rd Episode
Эпизод 23
전설선언!
Legend Declaration!
암흑수 드라고버스트 탄생!!
The Birth of Dark Beast Dragoburst!
(en: Fire and Ice)
마그마 파이어 브레이크!
Magma Fire Break!
블리자드 로드!
Blizzard Rod!
통신 영상이 찍은 영상이야.
This video was taken by communication satellite.
불과 얼음의 저 공격. 대단한 파괴력이었어.
The attack of fire and ice. That sure was a destructive force.
쟤들 대체 누구야? 어디서 온 거야?
Who the heck are they? Where did they come from?
몰라. 데이터로 추적했는데도 너무 빨라서 포착 불가능했어.
I don't know. I couldn't track them because they were too fast.
비행 속도도 경이적이라는 건가.
So their flight speed also is wonderful.
적인지 아군인지 그것만이라도 알고 싶다만...
I want to know if they're our friends or enemies...
경계 경보야!
Warning alarm!
미확인 비행 물체가 접근 중이야!
An unidentified flying object is approaching!
뭐라고?!
What?!
조심해! 숙여!
Watch out! Get down!
운석이 추락했나?
Did a meteor fall?
타이거마루하고 로우가마루가 또 온 거 아냐?
Did Tigermaru and Rougamaru come to mess up again?
어쩌면 이 별을 침략하러 온 우주인일지도!
Maybe they're aliens who came to invade this planet!
어쩌면 팀 아키라 견학차 온 것일지도!
Maybe they're here to study Team Akira!
그렇구나! 날 보러 왔구나!
I see! They're here to see me!
농담은 그 정도로 끝내라.
That's enough joke for now.
폭발물이 아니면 좋겠는데.
I hope it doesn't explode.
어쨌든 조사해 보자.
Anyway, let's find out what it is.
할아버지!
Grandpa!
하지메 박사님!
Prof. Hajime!
하지메 박사 당당히 등장이다!
Pf. Hajime you've been waiting for is here!
얜 드라고플레임.
This guy is Dragoflame.
그리고 이 쪽은 드라고프리저.
And this is Dragofreezer.
-드라고플레임?
-드라고프리저?
-Dragoflame?
-Dragofreezer?
둘 다 드라고버스트를 지원하는 배틀 로봇이다.
Both are Dragoburst's supporting robots.
드라고버스트?
Dragoburst?
누구야, 그거?
Who's that?
얘들보다 강해?
Is it stronger than them?
박사님은 어떻게 그런 걸 알고 계세요?
How do you know such things?
알고 있었구나. 그 놈들의 정보!
You already knew about them!
알려 주세요! 놈들은 적입니까, 아군입니까! 목적은 뭡니까!
Tell us! Are they foes or friends? What are their objectives?
한번에 몰아서 묻지 마! 하나하나 설명할 테니까!
Don't you gather on me and ask like that! I'll explain everything one by one!
난 그걸 위해 돌아왔으니까!
I'm back to tell you about that!
그 때부터 몇 년 몇 개월이 지났나...
How many years and months have went since that...
그 연구소에서는 로봇 사회의 빛나는 미래를 위해
At that laboratory, they were developing the flawless and perfect battle robots
완전무결, 완벽을 위한 최고의 배틀 로봇을 개발하고 있었다.
for the shining future of society with robots.
그리고 우리 과학자 그룹은 결국에 완성했다.
And we scientists group have finally completed one.
마그마가 낳은 열혈검사 드라고플레임.
Magma-born Fiery Swordman Dragoflame.
눈보라가 낳은 냉혈현자 드라고프리저.
Snowstorm-born Cold-blooded Sage Dragofreezer.
그리고 인간과 동일한 수준의 지능과 의지를 가진,
And finally, Dragoburst is with the same level of intelligence and will, who controls Dragoflame and Dragofreezer.
드라고플레임과 드라고프리저를 제어, 조종하는 능력을 가진 궁극의 배틀 로봇, 드라고버스트.
사실은 류구에게 짜넣은 클러스터 시스템은 드라고버스트 용으로 내가 개발한 제어, 조종 시스템으로 발전, 응용한 거다.
Furthermore, Ryugu's Cluster System was originally made for Dragoburst, and it went through some modifications.
그러니까, 드라고버스트는 다이간다의 먼 선조!
That means, Dragoburst is a distant ancestor of Daigunder!
잠깐만. 나 처음 들어! 할아버지가 그런 연구소에서 일했다니!
Just a moment! You never told me you've worked in such laboratory!
아, 그랬냐? 뭐, 연구소에서 일하는 걸 관둔 것도 꽤 오래 전 일이니까.
Oh, didn't I? It's been quite a time since I stopped working at that laboratory.
왜 관뒀어?
Why did you quit?
폐쇄됐으니까.
Because it was shut down.
폐쇄? 연구소가?
The laboratory was shut down?
그렇다.
Yes.
어째서 폐쇄되었나요.
Why was it shut down?
파괴됐다. 드라고플레임과 드라고프리저에게.
It was destroyed by Dragoflame and Dragofreezer.
뭐라고?!
What?!
아니, 정확히는 드라고버스트가 파괴한 거지.
Well, to be exact, Dragoburst did it.
그건 드라고버스트를 처음 기동하는 기념적인 날이었지.
It happened on the commemorative day of activating Dragoburst for the first time.
메인 회로 기동 스위치를 누른 건 공동 연구자인 다이쿤 교수.
The one to press the main circuit activation switch was the co-researcher, Prof. Daikun.
그렇지만...
But...
드라고버스트의 명령으로 드라고플레임하고 드라고프리저는 연구소를 파괴했다.
By the order of Dragoburst, Dragoflame and Dragofreezer destroyed the laboratory.
그들은 밤하늘로 사라졌다. 그리고 다시는 모습을 드러내지 않았다.
They disappeared to the night sky. And they never showed themselves again.
드라고버스트 놈, 너무했어.
That Dragoburst guy is bad!
근데 왜 연구소를 부쉈대?
But why did he destroy the lab?
모른다. 나도 그 이유를 알고 싶다.
I don't know. I also want to know why.
사라진 드라고플레임과 드라고프리저가 왜 지금들어 다시 모습을 드러냈을까.
I wonder why did Dragoflame and Dragofreezer finally decide to show themselves again.
그들, 아니, 드라고버스트는 다이간다에게 흥미를 가졌을 지도 모르지.
It is possible they, no, Dragoburst has interest in Daigunder.
다이간다?
Daigunder?
그래. 류구도.
Yes. Including you, Ryugu.
어?
Huh?
그렇구나! 그래서 류구가 위험해 처했을 때 드라고플레임하고 드라고프리저가 도와줬구나!
I see! That's why Dragoflame and Dragofreezer helped us when Ryugu was in danger!
그 말은, 우리 동료라는 거네?
That means they're our friends!
-그치, 아키라?
-어!
-Do you agree, Akira?
-Yeah!
그렇게 결론내는 건 위험해.
It is dangerous to conclude that.
연구소를 파괴한 놈들이다. 뭔 생각일지 모른다.
They destroyed the lab. We do not know what they're thinking.
어쨌든 나는 여러 데이터를 바탕으로 드라고버스트의 행방을 쫒고 있다.
Anyway, I'm trying to find out where Dragoburst is, based on various data.
다들 도와줘라.
Everyone, help me.
-예!
-응!
-Got it!
-Yeah!
류구를 구하다니, 아, 무슨 고얀놈!
Saving Ryugu means, ah, they're scoundrels!
놈들은 대체 누구이오!
Who are they-gozaru?
마그마가 낳은 열혈검사 드라고플레임.
Magma-born Fiery Swordsman Dragoflame.
눈보라가 낳은 냉혈현자 드라고프리저.
Snowstorm-born Cold-blooded Sage Dragofreezer.
알고 있었나.
Did you know them?
둘 다 드라고버스트를 지원하는 배틀 로봇이다.
Both of them are battle robots that support Dragoburst.
드라고버스트?
Dragoburst?
인간과 동등한 지능과 의지를 가진 배틀 로봇이다. 그 전투 능력은 다이간다를 뛰어넘을지도 모른다.
He is a battle robot with the same level of intelligence and will with humans.
His fighting capabilites might be far above Daigunder.
다이간다를?
Daigunder?
-무무무슨!
-이 놈은 대체 뭣이오!
-W-w-w-what?!
-Who is this guy-gozaru?!
놈들의 파괴력을 원한다. 내 것으로 만들고 싶다.
I want their destructive capabilities. I want to make them mine.
아니, 만드는 거다.
I will make them mine.
잠깐, 마스터! 아, 우리 차레이오!
Wait, master! ah, it's our turn!
반드시 포획하겠소!
We'll catch them-gozaru!
맡기겠다.
I'm leaving it to you.
좋소!
Great!
왜 그래, 서봇?!
What's wrong, Supbot?!
이건...
Look...
고속도로 공사 현장이야.
It's a construction site at the highway.
대체 뭔 일이야?
What's going on there?
역시! 드라고플레임하고 드라고프리저다!
I knew it! They're Dragoflame and Dragofreezer!
안 되겠어. 다가갈 수가 없어.
This is not good. It's impossible to get nearby.
경찰력으로 놈들의 공격을 막는 건 무리다.
Police force isn't enough to stop their attacks.
-우리가 갈 수 밖에 없어.
-그래!
-It's a job for us.
-Yeah!
다들 가자!
Let's go, everyone!
폭투선언 다이간다
Bakutou Sengen Daigunder
Wild Fight Declaration Daigunder
Боевой претендент Дайгандер
by Subdivers
Russian TL by SutoKuroi
Subdivers 번역
폭투선언 다이간다
Bakutou Sengen Daigunder
Wild Fight Declaration Daigunder
Боевой претендент Дайгандер
by Subdivers
Russian TL by SutoKuroi
Subdivers 번역
파이어 애로!
Fire Arrow!
스펙터 슬래시!
Spector Slash!
파이터 체인지!
Fighter Change!
드라고플레임! 드라고프리저! 왜 이런 짓을 하는 거야!
Dragoflame! Dragofreezer! Why are you guys doing this?!
해 볼 거야모그?
Wanna fight-mogu?
이 목소리...
That voice...
드라고버스트다! 드라고버스트 목소리다!
It's Dragoburst! It's Dragoburst's voice!
뭔가 날아오고 있어!
Something's flying towards!
뭐라고?!
What?!
아키라, 하늘을 봐!
Akira, look at the sky!
하늘?
Sky?
여기로 오고 있어!
It's heading towards us!
이글 애로! 드리모그! 아키라를 보호해!
Eagle Arrow! Drimog! Protect Akira!
-맡겨 둬, 형님!
-알겠어모그!
-Leave it to us, bro!
-Understood-mogu!
데스펙터! 트라이혼! 저길 향해 쏴라!
Despector! Trihorn! Aim and shoot towards that!
OK, 보스!
OK, boss!
스펙터 슬래시!
Spector Slash!
티라노 슬래시!
Tyranno Slash!
본렉스!
Bonerex!
저게... 저게...
That... That must be...
드라고버스트.
Dragoburst.
괜찮아, 본렉스?
Are you alright, Bonerex?
그래. 데스펙터! 트라이혼!
Yes. Despector! Trihorn!
방심했어!
I let my guards down!
저 자식! 잘도 했겠다!
That bastard really did it!
이번엔 우리 차례야모그!
It's our turn now-mogu!
지옥에 보내 주자!
Let's send them to hell!
소용없다.
Futile.
애니멀 유닛과 다이노 유닛의 전투 능력으로는 날 쓰러뜨릴 수 없다.
Animal Unit and Dino Unit's battle capabilites are not enough to take me down.
뭐시라?
What?
나는 드라고플레임과 드라고프리저를 써서 네놈들의 힘을 완전히 파악했다.
I analyzed your powers fully using Dragoflame and Dragofreezer.
그리고 파괴 활동을 위해 여기에 불렀다.
And I called them to here for destructive activities.
모든 건 드라고버스트가 짠 함정었다는 건가!
So it means everything was Dragoburst's trap!
그래도 뭘 위해?
But, for what?
드라고버스트! 네 목적은 뭐야! 왜 우릴 불러낸 거야?
Dragoburst! What's your objective? Why did you lure us out?
다이간다를 내 파트너로 하기 위해서다.
To make Daigunder into my partner.
뭐?!
What?!
파트너!
Partner!
흥, 잘못 보면 안 되지. 난 팀 아키라의 일원이야. 그리고 아키라의 파트너야!
Hmph! Don't misjudge me! I am a member of Team Akira! I am Akira's partner!
그래, 그게 맞아!
Yeah, that's right!
뭐가 이상해!
What's so funny?!
네놈은 다루기 어렵겠지. 다이간다의 유래없는 능력을.
It must be difficult for you to control the unprecedented potential power of Daigunder.
그렇군! 드라고버스트가 노리는 건 역시 다이간다였군!
That's it! Dragoburst was looking for Daigunder!
큰일이에요! 이대로는 온 마을이 화재에 휩싸이고 말아요.
This is bad! The whole city will be on fire at this rate!
뭐야?!
What?!
여러분 모두 어서 피난하세요!
Everyone, please take shelter!
피해 지역은 숲이야. 이대로는 마을이 위험해.
The forest is on fire. The city is in danger!
알았어!
Got it!
모두 소화활동이야! 다들 가자!
Everyone, go extinguish fire! Let's go!
드라고플레임! 드라고프리저! 비켜!
Dragoflame! Dragofreezer! Get out of my way!
저들은 내 손발. 네놈의 명령 따위 안 듣는다.
They are my tools. They won't listen to your orders.
아키라! 류구!
Akira! Ryugu!
괜찮아! 여긴 우리에게 맡겨!
It's alright! Leave this to us!
너희들은 먼저 가! 어서!
You guys should go first! Hurry!
-알겠다! 가자!
-좋다!
-Understood! Let's go!
-Right!
좋아! 우리도 소화를 돕자.
Great! Let's help extinguishing fire, too.
네. 서봇, 긴급 출동이야.
Got it. Supbot, we're taking off!
드라고버스트! 네가 원하는 대로 다이간다로 합체시켜 주겠어!
Dragoburst! They'll combine into Daigunder, as you wanted!
그리고 너하고 대결이다!
And we'll fight against you!
류구! 건더! 헤드합체!
Ryugu! Gunder! Head Fusion!
폭투왕 다이간다!
Wild Fight King Daigunder!
파이터 체인지!
Fighter Change!
드라고버스트!
Dragoburst!
스펙터 슬래시!
Spector Slash!
테일 블레이드!
Tail Blade!
썬더 클로!
Thunder Claw!
클래시 뱅!
Clash Bang!
소화율 50. 70. 80%.
Extinguish rate 50. 70. 80%.
이대로라면 마을에 닿기 전에 끌 수 있겠어.
The fire will disappear before it reaches the city at this rate.
좋아, 힘내라, 서봇!
Great! Keep it up, Supbot!
가라, 다이간다!
Go, Daigunder!
피해, 다이간다!
Evade, Daigunder!
공격!
Attack!
방패로 변신했어!
It transformed into a shield!
마그마 다이나믹!
Magma Dynamic!
파이널 리볼버!
Final Revolver!
긴잔!
Ginzan!
다이간다를 쓰러뜨리는 건 나다! 네놈 따위가 파괴하게 둘 수는 없다!
I'll be the one to take down Daigunder! I won't let you destroy him!
긴잔. 자신의 의지로 움직이는 불쌍한 배틀 로봇.
Ginzan. You are a pathetic battle robot, who happens to be able to move on your free will.
뭐시라?
What?
프로페서 빅뱅 아래서 떨어져 자립하지 못하는 한 네놈은 다이간다를 쓰러뜨릴 수 없다.
As long as you work under Professor Big Bang and cannot live on your own, you will never take down Daigunder.
웃기지 마라! 그런 설교 따위 듣고 있을 여유 없다!
Don't fool around! I have no time for your gibberish!
긴잔! 아, 공격은 무용이오!
Ginzan! ah, attack is futile!
빅뱅의 명령, 그 놈을 포획하는 것이오!
Big Bang's order is to catch that guy-gozaru!
타이거! 로우가! 상하합체!
Tiger! Rouga! Up Down Fusion!
기동이도류 타이거 더블팽!
Mobile Dual Blade Tiger Doublefang!
훌륭히 포획하는 대공훈은 우리가 가져가겠다!
The great triumph of capturing with excellence will be ours!
합체 타이거검, 타이거 타츠마키기리!
Fusion Tiger Sword, Tiger Tatsumakigiri!
뭣이?!
What?!
움직일 수가! 어이, 어찌 된 것이요!
I can't move! What's happening to us?!
분하고 원통한, 아, 일단 퇴각!
Retreating for now, ah, of bitter disappointment!
다음에는 꼭 활약하겠소!
We'll be victorius when we appear again-gozaru!
아키라!
Akira!
다들!
Everyone!
불은 다 껐다!
All the fire is extinguished!
이제 안심이야모그!
You can relieve now-mogu!
나머지는 이 놈들을 지옥에 보내는 것 뿐이다!
The only remaining is sending those bastards to hell!
흥. 오늘은 방해꾼이 가득하군.
Hmph. There are too many hindrances today.
다시 보자, 다이간다.
See you again, Daigunder.
멈춰라!
Stop!
됐어, 긴잔!
Forget it, Ginzan!
산불은 다 껐어. 이제 됐잖아?
The mountain fire is now gone. So it's all good now!
그럼 제군, 안녕이다!
Then, everyone, bye!
-부탁해, 할아버지!
-드라고버스트가 어디 있는지 꼭 찾아내 줘!
-We're entrusting this on you, grandpa!
-Find out where Dragoburst is!
물론! 맡겨 둬라!
Of course! Leave it to me!
-안녕, 할아버지!
-다시 놀러 와!
-Bye-bye, grandpa!
-Come play again!
조심하세요!
Be careful!
날 파트너로 하고 싶다니, 대체 뭔 생각하는 걸까, 드라고버스트 놈?
I wonder what is Dragoburst really thinking, for wanting to make as his partner.
강하고, 머리 좋고, 수수께끼 가득해. 이상한 배틀 로봇이야.
He's strong, smart, and full of mysteries. What a strange battle robot.
그 수수께끼도 언젠간 분명 풀리겠지. 아니, 풀어 보일 거야!
That mystery will be solved as time goes. No, we will solve that mystery!
그래!
Yeah!
끝없는 꿈을 꾸고 있어
Dreaming an endless dream
Я сон бесконечный вижу опять перед собой
몇번이고 쓰러져도
I fall down over and over again
Как упал, и лечу вниз вновь и вновь.
저 구름 위에는 분명히
Up over those clouds
Там, где-то в высотах, за чертой облаков
푸른 하늘이 펼쳐져 있을 거야
a blue sky awaits
голубое небо ждёт меня!
강해지기 위해서라면 누구도 혼자서는
To be strong, nobody can ever become
Сильным быть, чтоб никто превзойти не смог
강해지고 뜨거워질 수 없어
strong and hot, by oneself
Стать сильней, горячей, сам я хочу!
불꽃의 Fight Fight Fighting soul
Flaming fightin' fightin' fighting soul
Так гори, душа, душа бойца!
용기를 마주치는 그 때
When you face your courage
Смелость повстречай, и пусть ведёт она тебя в жизни.
다
녀
왔
어!
H
o
m
e!
Д
о
м
а!
다
녀
왔
어!
H
o
m
e!
Д
о
м
а!
다
녀
왔
어!
H
o
m
e!
Д
о
м
а!
느껴져 바로 너라는 게
I can feel it, yes, it's you
Я это чувствую, да, это ты!
다
녀
왔
어!
H
o
m
e!
Д
о
м
а!
다
녀
왔
어!
H
o
m
e!
Д
о
м
а!
다
녀
왔
어!
H
o
m
e!
Д
о
м
а!
둘은 서로의 영웅
The two are heroes of each other
Два героя - части одного, нерушимы связи,
질 수 없는 같은 내일을
They run towards to the same tomorrow
Вместе в новый день по одной тропе спешат
바라보고 달려
that they cannot lose
И не собьются с неё!
데스펙터하고 트라이혼이 물 부족으로 힘들어하는 사라하고 만났어!
Despector and Trihorn met Sarah, who was having trouble because of lack of water!
물이 없는 건 하워드라는 쪼잔한 놈이 혼자 다 차지해서 그래.
They lack water because some unfair guy named Howard is claiming all the water.
데스펙터!
Despector!
트라이혼!
Trihorn!
사라를 괴롭히는 나쁜 놈들을 해치워버려!
Deal with the bad guys who trouble Sarah!
지옥에 보내 주겠어!
They're going to hell!
폭투선언 다이간다의 다음 이야기!
이탈선언! 다시 만날 날까지!!
Next time on Wild Fight Declaration Daigunder!
Breakaway Declaration! Until We Meet Again!!